♪Don't feel sad for the fallen flowers♪
♪ لا تشعر بالحزن على الزهور الحزينة ♪
♪Falling in the mortal world♪
♪ يتظاهر في العالم الفاني ♪
♪Keep all the memories♪
♪ استمر في جميع الذكريات ♪
♪Can't find any peace anymore♪
♪ لا يمكن العثور على أي سلام بعد الآن ♪
♪The storms can't kill my passion♪
♪ العواصف لا يمكن أن تقتل حمايتي ♪
♪But I need to endure♪
♪ لكنني بحاجة إلى تحمل ♪
♪Be serious even though I'm naive♪
♪ كن جادا على الرغم من أنني ساذجة ♪
♪If this is the destined fate♪
♪ إذا كان هذا هو القدر المقدر ♪
♪Even if I'll be hurt♪
حتى ولو تأذيت ♪
♪I'll protect the people♪
♪ سأحمي الناس ♪
♪The mountains sun and moon can be my witnesses♪
♪ الجبال الشمس والقمر يمكن أن يكون شاهداي ♪
♪Full of passion♪
♪ مليء بالحماقة ♪
♪Deep love and hatred♪
♪ الحب والكراهية العميق ♪
♪Melts in my heart along with the snow♪
♪ يذوب في قلبي مع الثلج ♪
=Royal Rumours=
= الشائعات الملكية =
=Episode 11=
= الحلقة 11 =
Princess Jiamin.
الأميرة جيامين
Do you know how much we've lost
هل تعرف كم خسرنا
in a day?
في يوم واحد؟
About 132 taels and four strings of coin,
حوالي 132 تايل أربعة خيوط من العملة
not including the cost.
لا يشمل التكلفة
How do you know?
كيف تعرف؟
I took a glance
ألقيت نظرة خاطفة
when you did the calculation.
عندما فعلت الحساب
I've lost so much in a day.
فقدت الكثير في يوم واحد
What to do in the future?
ماذا أفعل في المستقبل؟
I'll figure out a way
سأكتشف طريقة
to make up for your deficit.
للتعويض عن عجزك
No worries.
لا قلقي
My family has plenty of money.
عائلتي لديها الكثير من المال
I don't want
لا أريد
to keep losing money like this.
الاستمرار في فقدان المال هكذا
It's time to eat. Come on.
حان وقت تناول الطعام، هيا
Go.
اذهب
May I ask?
هل يمكنني أن أسأل؟
Can we still dine here?
هل ما زلنا نتناول العشاء هنا؟
Yes.
نعم
It's free today.
إنه مجاني اليوم
You may always eat for free
يمكنك دائما تناول الطعام مجانا
if you're Longjing Street residents.
إذا كنت من سكان شارع لونغجينغ
We are Longjing Street residents.
نحن سكان شارع لونغجينغ
Yes.
نعم
Are you sure?
هل أنت متأكدة؟
Today is the first time
اليوم هو المرة الأولى
I see
فهمت
people from Longjing Street.
الناس من شارع لونغجينغ
Hong.
اهونغ
Come and serve the customers.
تعال لخدمة الزبائن
Yes, Miss.
نعم يا آنسة
You...
أنت
Don't you work for the Hua family's shop?
ألا تعمل متجر عائلة هوا؟
I...
أنا...
Yes.
نعم
You work for the Hua family?
هل تعمل من أجل عائلة هوا؟
Wait.
انتظر
Hua Liuli actually asks her people
هوا ليولي تطلب من شعبها في الحقيقة
to come and dine at my place for free?
أن يأتي لتناول الطعام في منزلي مجانا؟
Hasn't she gone too far?
ألم تذهب بعيدا؟
Princess.
يا برينسيس
Well...
إذن
Even when they work for the Hua family,
حتى عندما يعملون عائلة هوا
we should keep our promise
يجب أن نفي بوعدنا
as long as they're from Longjing Street.
طالما أنهم من شارع لونغجينغ
We didn't say
لم أقل
we wanted to dine for free.
أردنا أن نتناول العشاء مجانًا
It's nearby.
إنه قريب
You treat your customers like this.
أنت تعامل زبائنك هكذا
We don't want any meal.
لا نريد أي وجبة
Let's go.
لنذهب
- Wait. - Wait, dear customers.
- انتظري - مهلًا أيها الزبائن الأعزاء
Let's go. We aren't dining here.
هيا بنا نحن لا نتناول الطعام هنا
I'm Prince Ying.
أنا الأمير ينغ
Can you
هل يمكنك
tell me
أخبرني
why Longjing Street residents won't come?
لماذا شارع لونغجينغ لن يأتي المقيمون؟
After we're hired
بعد أن يتم توظيفنا
by Princess Hua,
من قبل الأميرة هوا
we're given shops
لقد أعطيت متاجر
to manage alone.
للإدارة وحدها
Not only we're given salaries,
ليس فقط يتم الحصول على الرواتب
we're viewed as shop owners.
يُنظر إلينا على أننا أصحاب متجر
We even have shares after making money.
حتى أن لدينا أسهم بعد الحصول على المال
This explains why I didn't see
هذا يفسر سبب عدم رؤية
people from Longjing Street today.
الناس من شارع لونغجينغ اليوم
They all were working.
كانوا جميعا يعملون
We're doubtful
نحن مشكوك في أمرنا
before that.
قبل ذلك
Isn't this the first day?
أليس هذا أول يوم؟
The shops of Princess Hua have made money.
محلات الأميرة هوا لقد كسبت المال
Also,
وأيضًا
she didn't hesitate at all.
لم تتردد على الإطلاق
She gave us the share of earnings.
أعطتنا نصيب من الإيرادات
How could you say that about her?
كيف يمكنك قول ذلك عنها
Let's go.
لنذهب
Come on.
هيا
I get it now.
فهمت الآن
I've lost.
لقد فقدت
Princess Hua
الأميرة هوا
is certainly better than me.
بالتأكيد أفضل مني
Princess Jiamin.
الأميرة جيان مين
Am I no better than others
ألست أفضل من الآخرين
in everything?
في كل شيء؟
My father does not favour me as much as he favours Crown Prince.
والدي لا يفضلني بقدر ما يفضل ولي عهد
I wanted to do something to draw my father's attention,
أردت القيام بشيء ما لجذب انتباه والدي
but I didn't do it as well as Princess Hua.
لكنني لم أفعل ذلك مثل الأميرة هوا
I'm indeed poor in everything.
أنا فقيرة في كل شيء بالفعل
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعلين؟
Are you admitting defeat already?
هل تعترف بالهزيمة بالفعل؟
The winner is the one who has the last laugh.
الفائز هو الشخص الذي لديه الضحكة الأخيرة
I'll go to my father tomorrow
سأذهب إلى والدي غدا
to ask for more money.
لطلب المزيد من المال
Princess.
الأميرة
Did you see
هل رأيتما
the smile on their faces just now?
الابتسامة على وجوههم قبل القليل؟
Princess Hua can let them
الأميرة هوا يمكنها السماح لهم
live and work in peace
العيش والعمل في سلام
even without money.
حتى من دون المال
I've lost the people's heart.
لقد فقدت قلب الناس
I've lost this time.
لقد خسرت هذه المرة
I'm convinced.
أنا مقتنع
Even when I don't have much ability,
حتى عندما لا يكون لدي الكثير من القدرة
I have the courage to admit defeat.
لدي الشجاعة للاعتراف بالهزيمة
However, our shop
ومع ذلك، فإن متجرنا
has earned a lot of reputation.
قد اكتسب الكثير من السمعة
You don't have to be
ليس عليك أن تكون
so upset.
منزعج جدًا
That's because you're helping me.
هذا لأنك تساعدني
Who'd compliment me?
من سيمدحني؟
Says who?
من؟
My father, Empress Dowager,
والدي، إمبراطورة
the officials
المسؤولون
and the people.
أم الشعب
Who would compliment me?
من سيمدحني؟
I think you're good.
أعتقد أنك بخير
Princess Jiamin.
الأميرة جيامين
Don't comfort me.
لا تواسيني
I'm not.
لست كذلك
You're different since you're born.
أنت مختلفة منذ أن وُلدت
You have strong confidence.
لديك ثقة كبيرة
When others are frustrated,
عندما يشعر الآخرون بالإحباط
you encourage them.
أنت تشجعهم
Everyone likes you.
الجميع يحبونك
I'll figure out a way
سأكتشف طريقة
to make up for your deficit.
للتعويض عن عجزك
Also,
وأيضًا
you mustn't give up.
يجب ألا تستسلمي
You're great.
أنت رائعة
Princess Jiamin.
الأميرة جيامين
You're also great,
أنتِ رائعة أيضا
because you see
لأنك ترى
the strength in me.
القوة في شخصيتي
It means you have a good eye.
هذا يعني أن لديك عين جيد
Is there nothing else?
ألا شيء آخر؟
I'm a brilliant person.
أنا شخص رائع
I shouldn't be sad.
لا يجب أن أشعر بالحزن
I should think about
يجب أن أفكر
whether it's due to
ما إذا كان ذلك راجعا
my excellence
امتيازي
that makes Princess Hua think
مما يجعل الأميرة هوا تعتقد
that she has to work harder
أنها مضطرة إلى العمل بجهد أكبر
to match me.
لمطابقتي
That's why she's come up
لهذا السبب جاءت
with this idea.
بهذه الفكرة
Princess Jiamin.
الأميرة جيامين
Do you agree
هل توافقين
with me?
معي؟
I also forgot a strength of yours.
كما نسيت قوة لك
What is it?
ما الأمر؟
You're highly imaginative.
أنت ابتكارية للغاية
Why is she angry again?
لماذا هي غاضبة مرة أخرى؟
Is it because
هل هذا لأن...
she's stressed out
إنها متوترة
by my excellence?
من خلال امتيازي؟
Miss.
الآنسة
The snack street
الشارع الوجبات الخفيفة
is even merrier today.
حتى مرح اليوم
Our milk tea shop in particular
متجر الحليب لدينا بشكل خاص
has a long queue.
لديه طابور طويل
Is it true?
هل هذا صحيح؟
That's awesome.
هذا رائع
I also heard
سمعت أيضا
that Yun Han drank our milk tea
أن يون هان شربت شاي الحليب لدينا
in public at Jinling Garden.
في حديقة جين لينغ
It drew the crowd.
سحبت الحشد
Is that the gift mentioned
هل هذه الهدية المذكورة
by Crown Prince?
من قبل ولي عهد؟
Miss.
الآنسة
How is it related
كيف علاقة ذلك
to Crown Prince?
بولي عهد؟
Miss.
الآنسة
Have we won then?
هل فزنا إذن؟
Where's Princess Hua?
أين الأميرة هوا؟
I'm here.
أنا هنا
Please accept the imperial decree.
يرجى قبول المرسوم الإمبراطوري
(Imperial Decree)
(مرسوم إمبراطوري)
By the imperial decree,
بالمرسوم الإمبراطوري
the daughter of Protector General,
ابنة المحمي العام
Hua Liuli,
هوا ليولي
is both virtuous and talented.
فاضلة وموهوبة في الوقت نفسه
She hires people on merit.
إنها تستخدم الناس على أساس الجدارة
She calmly responded during the Ceremonial Officer's
استجابت بهدوء خلال الفحص
examination.
الامتحان
She cultivates barren lands and trains businessmen.
إنها تقوم بزراعة الأراضي القاحلة وتدريب رجال الأعمال
It's sound governance,
إنه الحكم السليم
which impresses me.
مما يفزعني
Princess Hua is specially granted
يتم منح الأميرة هوا بشكل خاص
with the position of Ceremonial Officer
بمنصب مسؤول مراسم
to lead the peace talk
لقيادة محادثات السلام
at States Assembly.
في جمعية المقاطعات
The end.
انتهيت
Thank you, Your Majesty.
شكرا لك يا صاحب الجلالة
Miss.
الآنسة
The official uniform is really nice.
الزي الرسمي جميل حقا
Move, Miss.
تحرك يا آنسة
Go to the imperial court.
اذهب إلى العودة الإمبراطورية
(Hua Mansion)
(طائفة هوا)
Go.
اذهب
You must use your brain more.
يجب أن تستخدم عقلك أكثر
Put in effort
تبذل جهدا
for our country.
لبلدنا
- I don't know - (Why do we have to)
- أنا لا أعرف - (لماذا يجب علينا)
- what you've been thinking. - (get up so early for the assembly?)
- ما كنت تفكر فيه - (انهضي باكرًا...)
(I'm so sleepy.)
"أشعر بالنعاس الشديد"
It's really delicious.
إنه لذيذ حقا
Thank you.
شكرا لك
Uncle Tian.
العم تيان
Why does everyone have to dine here?
لماذا يتناول الجميع العشاء هنا؟
It's the benevolence of His Majesty.
إنه خير جلالة الإمبراطور
His Majesty takes the hard work of his officers into account.
جلالة الإمبراطور يأخذ العمل الجاد من الضباط التابعين له
Hence, this meal is provided.
ومن هنا، يتم توفير هذه الوجبة
Why is your meal
لماذا وجبتك
different from mine?
مختلفةً عني؟
I'm a third-rank officer.
أنا ضابط من الرتبة الثالثة
I'm definitely different from you, who is just
أنا مختلفة بالتأكيد منك، التي هي فقط
the Ceremonial Officer.
مسؤول الاحتفال
I see.
فهمت
It seems
يبدو أن
Uncle Zhu's position isn't really high.
موقف العم تشو ليس جيدا حقا
Minister Tian.
الوزير تيان
What do you think if I
ما رأيك إذا كنت
complain about Ceremonial Officer's
عن زميلة الحارس
rudeness during breakfast
الصفاء خلال الفطور
and plead to deduct
والمناداة بالاستيلاء
one month's worth
لمدة شهر واحد
of her salary?
من مرتبها؟
Supervisor Zhao.
المشرف تشاو
What's the matter, Princess Hua?
ما الأمر يا أميرة هوا؟
Minister Zhu hasn't touched his food today.
الوزير تشو لم لمست طعامه اليوم
I guess
أعتقد
the meal
الوجبة
doesn't match his appetite.
لا يضاهي شهيته
Put it away for him.
ضعيه له
Officer Hua, you...
أيها الموظف هوا، أنت...
Arrival of Crown Prince.
وصول ولي عهد
- Your Highness.
- صاحب السمو
Aren't you
ألست
the Ceremonial Officer?
المسؤولة عن الحفل؟
How do you feel about
كيف تشعر
the first imperial court assembly?
الجمعية الإمبراطورية الأولى؟
Come on.
هيا
- They...
- إنهم... - هم... -
Ignore the petty matter.
تجاهلا المسألة التافهة
What's happening?
ماذا يحدث؟
Continue your meal.
استمري في وجبتك
Princess.
الأميرة
You brought me out just like this.
لقد أخرجتني هكذا
Aren't you afraid of being reported by the Censorate
ألا تخافين من كونك تم الإبلاغ عنه من قبل وحدة التفتيش المشتركة
when he knows this?
عندما يعرف ذلك؟
He's deducted a month of salary
تخصم منه مرتب شهر
of mine.
من أجلي
A meal will be provided
سيتم تقديم وجبة
to all officers
لجميع الضباط
after every morning assembly.
بعد كل اجتماع صباح اليوم
You still have to take note of
لا يزال عليك أن تحيط علما
the official etiquette while dining.
آداب السلوك الرسمية أثناء تناول الطعام
You're quite cute
أنت ظريف جدًا
in this small official uniform.
في هذا الزي الرسمي الصغير
Your Highness.
سموك
Being an officer is really tiring.
أن يكون ضابطا متعبا حقا
I actually want you to look at
في الواقع أريدك أن تنظر
the Longjing Street construction with me.
شارع لونغجينغ البناء معي
Come on,
هيا
Ceremonial Officer.
موظفة مراسم
You should carry out the duty of your position.
يجب أن تقوم واجب منصبك
Let the officer of Works Ministry come.
دع مسؤول وزارة الأشغال يأتي
I'm here.
أنا هنا
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
I was supervising the work.
كنت أشرف على العمل
I didn't notice your arrival.
لم ألاحظ وصولك
Were you supervising it?
هل كنت تشرف على الأمر؟
How many days have passed?
كم يوم مرت؟
What's with the slow progress?
ما خطب التقدم البطيء؟
Well...
إذن
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
It's because...
ذلك لأن...
It's because the owner of this place
لأن صاحب هذا المكان
claimed
ادعى
that he's your uncle.
أنه عمك
He wouldn't let me touch it.
لن يسمح لي بملمسها
So...
لذلك
Where is he?
أين هو؟
He's nearby.
إنه قريب
Let him come.
دعه يأتي
Noted.
حسنا
Your Highness.
سموك
Are you considered
هل تعتبر
my uncle?
عمي؟
Yes.
نعم
I don't expect you to remember me.
لا أتوقع منك أن تتذكرني
Have I been
هل كنت
too kind to you?
لطيفة جدا بالنسبة لك؟
Why don't I recall meeting
لماذا لا أتذكر الاجتماع
an insensible person like you
شخص غير معقول مثلك
when I was little?
عندما كنت صغيرا؟
Your Highness, have you
صاحبة السمو، هل نسيت
forgotten?
نسيت؟
When you're five years old...
عندما يكون عمرك خمس سنوات...
What happened when he's five years old?
ماذا حدث عندما كان يبلغ من العمر خمس سنوات؟
His Highness visited his maternal relatives
زار سموه أقاربه من الأمهات
with Empress Gonghui when he's five years old.
مع إمبراطورة غونغوي عندما يكون عمره خمس سنوات
They passed by a garden
مرروا بواسطة حديقة
and saw a group of children climbing trees.
ورأوا مجموعة من تسلق الأشجار
His Highness joined them in climbing the trees.
انضم إليهم سموه في تسلق الأشجار
Unexpectedly,
على غير المتوقع
when His Highness climbed up...
عندما تسلق سموه...
How dare you.
كيف تجرؤ؟
You're deceiving everyone
أنت تخداع الجميع
using my mother's name.
باستخدام اسم أمي
The States Assembly
جمعية الولايات
is a national event.
حدث وطني
How dare you stop it!
كيف تجرؤ على إيقافه!
I dare not.
أنا لا أجرؤ
Take him away
خذه بعيدا
and punish him accordingly.
ومعاقبتهم وفقا لذلك
- Yes.
- نعم
Have mercy on me, Your Highness!
ارحمني يا صاحب السمو!
No one must disrupt
لا أحد
the States Assembly
جمعية الولايات
or he or she will be punished severely!
أو سوف يعاقب بشدة!
- Yes.
- نعم
Yes.
نعم
Work now.
اعملا الآن
Hurry up!
أسرع!
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
Stop being mad.
توقف عن الغضب
Don't you think I'm fierce?
ألا تظن أنني شرس؟
You're quite fierce,
أنت شرس جدا
but I think
لكنني أعتقد
you're thinking about
أنت تفكر في
the people,
الشعب
not yourself.
ليس نفسك
That man
هذا الرجل
is your mother's relative.
هو قريب أمك
You didn't bend the law for your own interests.
لم تلتق القانون من أجل مصالحك الخاصة
Your mother wouldn't blame you.
لن تلومك أمك
She'd praise you instead.
كانت ستمددك بدلًا منها
So,
لذلك
what happened after that?
ماذا حدث بعد ذلك؟
Back then,
آنذاك
when I wanted to start climbing,
عندما أردت أن أبدأ التسلق
a child
طفل
fell from the tree.
سقط من الشجرة
I caught him by my arms.
أمسكت به ذراعيّ
You're five years old.
عمرك خمس سنوات
Didn't you say
ألم تقل
you're unwell
أنك بخير
when you're little?
عندما تكون صغيرا؟
I was in good health for a while
كنت في صحة جيدة لفترة
just like you did.
كما فعلت تمامًا
However, being five years old...
لكن، كوني تبلغ من العمر خمس سنوات
Right.
صحيح
It's a long journey to the court assembly.
إنها رحلة طويلة إلى جمعية المحكمة
I bet you didn't have enough sleep.
أراهن أنك لم تنامي بما يكفي
It's hard on you.
هذا صعب عليك
If you want to go back to Jinque Street...
إذا أردت العودة إلى شارع جين...
Longjing Street is where
شارع لونغجينغ هو أين
I'll work in the future.
سأعمل في المستقبل
It's near the western suburb.
إنه بالقرب من الضاحية الغربية
I want to walk there.
أريد أن أسير هناك
Fine.
حسنا
I can see you
أستطيع أن أراك
when I'm inspecting Longjing Street.
عندما أقوم بالتفتيش على شارع لونغجينغ
- Crown Prince.
- ولي عهد
Move.
تحرك
(It's not like they see Crown Prince.)
(إنه ليس وكأنهم يرون ولي عهد)
(It's like they see a ghost.)
(يبدو أنهم يرون شبح)
I don't think I should go.
لا أظن أن عليّ الذهاب
(I should cheer him up.)
(يجب أن أشجعه)
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
Why don't you come to my home?
لماذا لا تأتي إلى منزلي؟
I happen to have something for you.
صادف أن يكون لدي شيء لك
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
What's this?
ما هذا؟
Do you remember
هل تتذكرين
an empty box
صندوق فارغ
in Eastern Palace?
في القصر الشرقي؟
You said it's called Snow Mountain,
قلت إنه يُدعى جبل الثلج
but after getting it,
ولكن بعد الحصول عليه
I don't get to find
لا أجد
the mountain.
الجبل
It's just a box.
إنه مجرد صندوق
Snow Mountain
جبل الثلج
must have melted on the way here.
يجب أن يكون قد ذاب في الطريق إلى هنا
It melted?
لقد ذاب؟
When I get a chance,
عندما تتاح لي الفرصة
I'll make it again for you.
سأعده لك مرة أخرى
So this is Snow Mountain.
إذًا هذا هو جبل الثلج
Yes.
نعم
I promised to make it
وعدت أن أجعله
for you.
لك
Therefore,
لذلك
I started making it
بدأت أجعله
when the weather was warm.
عندما كان الطقس دافئًا
Your Highness.
سموك
This is delivered from the border.
هذا يتم تسليمه من الحدود
The box is kind of light.
الصندوق نوع من الضوء
Could there be an insect inside?
هل يمكن أن يكون هناك حشرة في الداخل؟
Shall we open it to see?
هل نفتحها لرؤية هذا؟
It has nothing.
لا شيء فيه
So you didn't mean
لذلك لم تقصد أنني
to scare me by sending
لإخافتي عن طريق إرسال
Snow Mountain at that time.
الجبل الثلج في ذلك الوقت
Every item that I sent
كل بند أرسلته
to you
عليك
wasn't meant to scare you.
لم يكن مُقدّرا لإخافتك
Were you
هل كنت
scared?
خائفة؟
How was it possible?
كيف يمكن ذلك؟
This Snow Mountain
هذا الجبل الأسود
is a seasonal food.
هو طعام موسمي
Everyone loves new things.
الجميع يحب أشياء جديدة
No matter how good the thing is,
لا يهم مدى جودة الشيء
it won't be favoured by the people
لن يحظى بتأييد الشعب
if it remains the same.
إذا ظل على حاله
So I
لذلك
tried adding
حاولت إضافة
different spices,
التوابل المختلفة
fruit jam,
أشعة الفاكهة
sweets, cake
حلوى وكعكة
and many other ways of enjoying it.
وطرق أخرى كثيرة للاستمتاع به
It could be renewed from time to time
يمكن تجديده من وقت لآخر
based on seasons and preferences.
استنادا إلى المواسم والأفضليات
This is Persimmon Snow.
هذا هو الشعار الخاطر
I specially made this
لقد صنعت هذا خصيصا
for you.
هذه لك
I use
أنا أستخدم
persimmon kept in winter.
تم الاحتفاظ بالخرمى في الشتاء
The jam is made fresh.
الأحمق يصبح طازجا
Try it.
جربيه
Persimmon Snow.
المشاهدة
If you have time,
إذا كان لديك وقت
I also want to bother you
أريد أيضا إزعاجك
to bring it to both
لإحضاره إلى كلا
Empress Dowager
إمبراطورة الأرملة
and the Third Prince to try.
والأمير الثالث في المحاولة
Also,
وأيضًا
if it's possible,
إذا كان ذلك ممكنا
I also want the people
أريد أيضا أن يجرب
in the shop to try it.
في المتجر لتجربتها
I think it'll boost
أعتقد أنها ستعزز
the sales...
المبيعات...
What's wrong?
ما الخطب؟
Is cow milk added?
هل أضيف حليب البقر؟
I specially added it.
أضيفت إليه خصيصا
Your Highness.
سموك
What's wrong with cow milk?
ما هو الخطأ في حليب البقر؟
I'm not drunk.
أنا لست ثملة
(Limited supply) Stop pushing.
(إمدادات محدودة) توقف عن الدفع
Line up properly.
اصطفوا بشكل صحيح
One by one.
واحد تلو الآخر
Take it easy. Line up properly.
خذ الأمر سهلًا، اصطفوا جيدًا
Next.
التالي
- Next. - Here you go.
- التالي - تفضلي
One for me.
واحدة لي
Here you go.
ها أنت ذا
How many people are in front?
كم عدد الأشخاص الذين أمامي؟
- We aren't there yet. - Line up properly.
- لم نصل بعد - اصطفوا بشكل صحيح
It's my turn at last.
حان دوري أخيرا
- Next. - Here you go.
- التالي - تفضلي
♪The spring breeze carries the song away♪
♪ نسيم الربيع تحمل بعد الأغنية ♪
♪The mountain and river is incomparable to you♪
♪ الجبل والنهر لا يمكن مقارنته بك ♪
Next.
التالي
Give it to him.
أعطه له
Minmin.
مين
I want to buy
أريد أن أشتري
Snow Mountain later.
جبل الثلج في وقت لاحق
If you go,
إذا ذهبت
you'll be
ستكون عدوا لك
my sworn enemy.
عدوي تحت القسم
Wait.
انتظر
Why do you hate Hua Liuli?
لماذا تكره هوا ليولي؟
I'm not even allowed to buy Snow Mountain.
لا يُسمح لي حتى لشراء جبل الثلج
Is it so good?
هل هي لذيذة هكذا؟
Is our cheese cake not nice?
هل كعكة الجبن لدينا ليست جيدة
No.
لا
I'm going back to have ten cheese cakes.
سأعود لتناول عشر كعكات جبن
It's nice.
إنه لطيف
Minmin.
مين
(Thanks to Third Prince,)
(شكرا للأمير الثالث)
(I've made your painting)
(لقد صنعت لوحتك)
(into a banner.)
(إلى لافتة)
(It's extremely effective.)
(إنها بالغة الفعالية)
(It's spread by word of mouth.)
(إنه ينتشر بكلام فمي)
(Hua Liuli) (Everyone says the painting)
(هوا ليولي) (الجميع يقول اللوحة)
(is vivid and cute)
(حافية وظريفة)
(with its charm.)
(بسحره)
Princess Hua got someone
الأميرة هوا حصلت على شخص ما
to deliver this Snow Mountain in a special box
لتسليم جبل الثلج هذا في صندوق خاص
by a horse.
بحصان
Eat it
تناولوه
before it melts.
قبل أن يذوب
(Righteous Radiance)
(الإشعاع الصالحي)
(However, I'm worried.)
(ومع ذلك، أنا قلق)
(If you dislike it,)
(إذا كنت لا تحبها)
(you may bother Crown Prince)
(يمكنك إزعاج ولي عهد)
(to relay the message.)
(لنقل الرسالة)
(I'll withdraw it.)
(سأسحبها)
Yuanhong.
يوانهونغ
Have you drawn another painting?
هل رسمت لوحة أخرى؟
Is this
هل هذه
Hua Liuli?
هوا ليولي؟
Excellent drawing skills.
مهارات رسم ممتازة
It's extremely adorable.
إنها ظريفة جدًا
What's the matter?
ما الأمر؟
I like it.
يعجبني هذا
It has to be you.
يجب أن يكون أنت
Hua Liuli.
هوا ليولي
Princess.
الأميرة
This sunset colour
لون الغروب هذا
is a new colour of the south-western dye shop.
لون جديد متجر الأصباغ الجنوبي غرب
They produce only two dresses.
تنتج فستانين فقط
One has been sent
تم إرسال واحدة
to the palace
إلى القصر
as a tribute to Consort Xian.
تكريما للقرينة شيان
Another has been sent
تم إرسال آخر
to our mansion.
إلى قصرنا
Look.
انظر
This dress matches
هذا الثوب يطابق
your favourite bangle well.
العنقاء المفضل لديك جيدا
This is it then.
هذا هو إذن
What's going on?
ماذا يجري؟
The bangle...
المأدبة...
Have you been drinking too much cow milk?
هل كنت تشربي الكثير من حليب البقر؟
You've gained weight.
ازداد وزنك
I've gained weight?
ازداد وزني؟
It's you instead.
إنها أنت بدلًا منها
I'm the slimmest throughout the capital.
أنا أقصى عقبة في جميع أنحاء العاصمة
Use your strength, Princess.
استخدمي قوتك يا أميرة
I'm using it.
أنا أستخدمها
Princess, think about Princess Hua.
الأميرة، فكري في الأميرة هوا
What?
كيف؟
How did you come up with this trick?
كيف توصلت إلى هذه الحيل؟
It hurts me.
إنه يؤلمني
Stupid Hua Liuli.
هوا ليولي غبية
Yes, Princess Hua.
نعم، الأميرة هوا
Minmin, go to the western suburb.
مينمين، اذهبي إلى الضاحية الغربية
Buy Snow Mountain for me.
اشتر لي جبل سنو
I'm craving for it.
أنا أشتهي إليه
I won't go.
لن أذهب
Your father refused to go.
رفض والدك الذهاب
Are you learning from him?
هل تتعلم منه؟
I don't want to go.
لا أريد الذهاب
I haven't given you
لم أعطيك المال هذا الشهر
pocket money this month.
الجيب هذا الشهر
Think properly.
فكري بشكل صحيح
I'll go.
سأذهب
Good.
جيد
(Yunzhong Hall)
(قاعة يونزهونغ)
This is what you get for helping
هذا ما تحصل عليه للمساعدة
Crown Prince and Hua Liuli.
و هوا ليولي
Master also let me remind you
المعلم أيضا دعني أذكرك
about
بشأن
your real master.
معلمك الحقيقي
If
لو
Hua Liuli becomes the Ceremonial Officer,
أصبحت هوا ليولي مسؤول الاحتفال
who...
من...
who will worry the most?
من سيكون أكثر قلقا؟
Relay this message to Master.
انقل هذه الرسالة إلى المعلم
He'll know what to do.
سيعرف ماذا يفعل
(Confidential) Master.
"سري" معلمي
Do as Yun Han says.
افعل كما يقول يون هان
Yes.
نعم
(Milk Tea Shop)
(مطعم الشاي)
Not bad.
لست سيئة
They're way smarter than those
إنها أكثر ذكاء
from Jinpo.
من جينبو
It seems
يبدو أنه
I should go out more often.
يجب أن أخرج أكثر
Otherwise,
خلاف ذلك
they'll blame me for not giving them a chance.
سوف يلومونني على عدم بإعطائهم فرصة
Is it one for each?
هل هو واحد لكل منا
Yes.
نعم
One moment, please.
لحظة من فضلك
Pour more fruit jam.
اسكب المزيد من الفاكهة
Yes, Miss.
نعم، الآنسة
Red Bean.
أحمر بان
Why don't you wear your hat
لماذا لا ترتدي قصتك
properly today?
بشكل صحيح اليوم؟
Is it skewed?
هل هو مزيف؟
Dressing neatly every day
الملابس المكبرة كل يوم
is the basic requirement of our shop.
هو المطلب الأساسي لمدرنا
You should take note next time.
يجب أن تأخذا علما في المرة القادمة
Yes, Miss.
نعم يا آنسة
Mung Bean.
مونغ بان
Miss.
الآنسة
You must confirm the freshness
يجب أن تؤكدي الطاولة
of the fruits repeatedly.
من الفاكهة مرارا وتكرارا
There mustn't be rotten fruits
يجب ألا تكون هناك ثمار سيئة
mixed in the jam.
مختلط في البرج
It'll affect the texture.
سيؤثر ذلك على النسيج
Sure, Miss.
بالطبع، الآنسة
Miss.
الآنسة
You're unwell.
أنت بخير
Don't always work so hard.
لا تجهد نفسك دائمًا
It's my duty.
إنه واجبي
I've just been appointed
لقد عينت للتو
as the Ceremonial Officer.
كمسؤول مراسم
I should do more
يجب أن أفعل المزيد
for the people.
للشعب
Yuan Wei.
يوان وي
Let's walk around Longjing Street.
دعنا نسير حول شارع لونغجينغ
Sure.
بالطبع
Song, we'll be heading to Longjing Street.
سونغ، سنكون متجهين إلى شارع لونغجينغ
Have a safe trip.
رحلة آمنة
Let's go.
لنذهب
(Longjing Street)
(شارع لونغجينغ)
(Kucha)
(كوتشا)
(Siam)
(كوتشا) 0سبتمبر0 (سيام) 0سبتمبر0 (غاوتتشانغ)
(Gaochang)
(غاوتشانغ)
(Jinpo)
(جينبو)
Miss.
الآنسة
There's no one here.
لا يوجد أحد هنا
It's cheerless.
هذا عديم الإحساس
Why don't we go back to the mansion?
لم لا نعد إلى القصر؟
State ministers have yet to arrive in the capital.
وزراء الدولة لم يعودوا على الوصول إلى العاصمة
It's surely cheerless.
إنه بالتأكيد بلا تشجيع
Yuan Wei.
يوان وي
I'm suddenly craving
أنا أشتهي فجأة
for the plum cake on Shijin Street.
لكعكة البرقوق في شارع شيجين
Buy some for me.
اشتري لي بعضًا منه
All right. I'm going now.
حسنًا، سأذهب الآن
(There're less people here.)
(هناك أشخاص أقل هنا)
(It's easier for them to act.)
(من الأسهل بالنسبة لهم التصرف)
It's you.
إنه أنت
If you have anything
إذا كان لديك أي شيء
for me,
نيابة عني
come to me tomorrow.
تعالي إليّ غدا
I'm still on duty today.
ما زلت في واجبي اليوم
Wait.
انتظر
So what if you're on duty?
ماذا إن كنت في الواجب إذًا؟
Are you allowed to bully me?
هل يُسمح لك بأن تتنمر عليّ؟
My mother asked me to buy
طلبت مني أمي أن أشتري
Snow Mountain.
جبل الثلج
The shop closed when I just arrived.
المتجر مغلق عندما وصلت للتو
Tell me.
أخبرني
Did you deliberately ask them to close the shop?
هل طلبت منهم عمدا بإغلاق المتجر؟
Jiamin.
جيامين
You must have misunderstood me.
لا بد أنك أسأت فهمي
We wouldn't close the shop
لن نغلق المتجر
for no reason.
لا سبب
It must be caused by
يجب أن يكون سببه
insufficient ingredients.
مكونات غير كافية
We won't turn down
لن نرفض
any customer.
أي زبائن
How about this?
ماذا عن هذا؟
Go back with me now.
عد معي الآن
I'll tell them
سأخبرهم
to specially make one for you.
أن يصنع لك واحدة خصيصا
Come on.
هيا
No.
لا
You must
يجب عليك
make it clear to me today.
أوضح لي اليوم
You even refuse to stay
حتى أنك ترفض البقاء
in the same place
في نفس المكان
with me.
معي
There's a problem with this house.
هناك مشكلة مع هذا المنزل
Hold your breath now.
احفظي أنفاسك الآن
(You can just kill me directly.)
(يمكنك فقط قتلي مباشرة)
(You use a drug.)
(يتعاطون المخدرات)
(It seems you're up to something else.)
(يبدو أنك حتى شيء آخر)
(The dumb Jiamin has got in the way.)
(وصل الحبيب جيامين إلى الطريق)
(I'll just turn this trick to my own use.)
(سأقوم بتحويل هذه الحيل فقط) إلى استخدامي الخاص
(She's really plump.)
(إنها ممتلئة حقًا)
Why are there two people?
لماذا هناك شخصان؟
Which one is Hua Liuli?
أي شخص هو هوا ليولي؟
I can't tell which is Hua Liuli
لا أستطيع أن أعرف أي هوا ليولي
either.
أيضا
Time is running out.
الوقت ينفد
Forget it. Take both away.
انس الأمر، خذي كليهما
Guard outside.
احرسه في الخارج
Don't let anyone in.
لا تدع أحدا يدخل
Yes.
نعم
Also, the two of you,
وأيضا، أنتما الاثنان
keep an eye on the two in the house.
راقب الاثنين في المنزل
Yes.
نعم
(Judging by the travelling time by carriage,)
(حكم من خلال السفر) الوقت عن طريق النقل
(it should've been quite a distance)
(كان ينبغي أن يكون بعيدا جدا)
(from the capital.)
(من العاصمة)
(It isn't difficult for me to escape alone,)
(ليس من الصعب عليّ) الهروب وحده
(but I have to seek another chance to ensure)
(ولكن يجب أن أسعى إلى تحقيق ذلك فرصة أخرى لكفالة)
(Jiamin's safety.)
(سلامة جيامين)
Do you still want to run?
هل ما زلت تريد الركض؟
Who is so ignorant?
من هو الجاهل جدا؟
How dare you tie me up.
كيف تجرؤ على تقييدي
I'll rip you apart.
سأرفقتك
Release me!
أطلق سراحي!
Do you think you can beat us?
هل تظن أن بإمكانك التغلب علينا؟
Don't waste your effort.
لا تبدد جهودك
You...
أنت...
You should wake up, too.
يجب أن تستيقظي أيضًا
Where am I?
أين أنا؟
What's going on?
ماذا يجري؟
Stay still.
لا تتحرك
Someone has tied us up.
قيّدنا أحدهم طريقنا
Can't you see?
ألا ترين؟
Who are you?
من أنت؟
Why did you tie us up?
لماذا ربطتنا؟
Do you want money?
هل تريد المال؟
My mother...
أمي...
Who is Princess Hua?
من هي الأميرة هوا؟
Do you want to catch Hua Liuli?
هل تريد الإمساك بهوا ليولي؟
She's Hua Liuli.
إنها هوا ليولي
She is.
إنها كذلك
It's her.
إنها هي
She's Hua Liuli.
إنها هوا ليولي
It really has nothing to do with me.
لا شيء علاقة لي حقا
It's really her.
إنها هي حقًا
You...
أنت...
Why are you doing this?
لماذا تفعل هذا؟
Fine.
حسنا
Since you say I am,
بما أنك تقولين إني بخير
I am.
بلى
It's really her.
إنها هي حقًا
Miss.
الآنسة
I'm the one who you're looking for.
أنا الشخص الذي تبحثين عنه
Princess Hua...
الأميرة هوا...
No.
لا
This lady is innocent.
هذه السيدة بريئة
Let her go.
دعها تذهب
It seems
يبدو أنه
you're Hua Liuli instead.
أنت هوا ليولي بدلا من ذلك
It's really her.
إنها هي حقا
You have the heart of a beast
لديك قلب الوحش
and you're scheming.
وأنت تحملين
Why don't you become a performer
لماذا لا تصبح المؤدية
when you're able to act so well?
عندما تكون قادرا على التصرف على نحو جيد؟
I'm so mad.
أنا غاضبة جدًا
Let me go.
دعني أذهب
I'm really not Hua Liuli.
أنا حقا لست هوا ليولي
I've said it's her.
لقد قلت إنها هي
I'll chop off your legs if you move again!
سأخلع ساقيك إن انتقلت مجددًا!
We'll kill you two
سوف نقتلكما
if you refuse to tell.
إذا رفضت معرفة ذلك
(It seems they don't mean)
(يبدو أنها لا تعني)
(to act now.)
(للتصرف الآن)
(They're bluffing.)
(إنهم خداعون)
We'll come back to you later.
سنعود إليك لاحقا
(There should be others)
(يجب أن يكون هناك آخرون)
(except them.)
(باستثناء)
Don't make any sound.
لا تصنع أي صوت
Evil woman.
امرأة شريرة
You deliberately dragged me into this.
لقد جرتني عمدا إلى هذه
You even want the assassins
أنت حتى تريد القاتل
to mistake me for you.
أن يخطئي من أجلك
Use your brain.
استخدمي عقلك
They're looking for me.
إنهم يبحثون عني
Would they've spared you
هل كانوا سيجنبونك
after identifying me?
بعد تحديد هويتي؟
There'd only be one outcome for you.
لن تكون هناك سوى نتيجة واحدة لك
They will kill me
سوف يقتلونني
to silence me.
لإسكات أنا
You're smart.
أنت ذكي
So what we should do now
ما يجب علينا فعله الآن
is to confuse them.
هو الخلط بينهما
Then we'll be safe for now.
إذن سنكون آمنين في الوقت الحالي
Maybe there's a chance to be saved.
ربما هناك فرصة لننقذها
What should we do?
ماذا يجب أن نفعل؟
Sleep for a while.
نومًا لبعض الوقت
Don't sleep.
لا تنام
Hua Liuli.
هوا ليولي
Stay close to me.
ابق قريبا مني
I'm a little scared.
أنا خائفة بعض الشيء
There's nothing to be scared of.
لا شيء يدعو للخوف
You're so timid.
أنت خجولة جدا
(Ankang Garden)
(حديقة آنكانغ)
Your Highness!
صاحب السمو!
You can't enter.
لا يمكنك الدخول
Miss has gone missing.
لقد فقدت الآنسة
Not just her.
ليست فقط هي
Princess Jiamin has also gone missing.
الأميرة جيامين فقدت أيضا
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
This...
هذا...
This is my princess's bangle.
هذه هي مأدبة الأميرة
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
This should be a kind of
يجب أن يكون هذا نوعا من أنواع المخدرات
rare hypnotising drug.
عقار نادر
Your Highness.
سموك
We discovered unknown blood stain
اكتشفنا لطخة دم غير معروفة
three miles outside Longjing Street.
على بعد ثلاثة أميال خارج شارع لونغجينغ
Go back first.
عد أولا
I'll do my best
سأبذل قصارى جهدي
to look for both princesses.
للبحث عن الأميرة
Miss has said that
لقد قالت الآنسة
you may seem
قد تبدو
unfriendly to outsiders,
غير صديق للغرباء
but you're actually the most reliable person.
لكنك في الحقيقة أكثر الأشخاص ثقة
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
We can only count on you.
يمكننا فقط الاعتماد عليك
Qi and Ba.
تشي وبا
- Yes.
- نعم
Jinling Garden.
حديقة جينلينغ
(Yunzhong Hall)
(قاعة يونزهونغ)
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
Deploy everyone in the capital.
نشر الجميع في العاصمة
Search for Hua Liuli.
البحث عن هوا ليولي
Yes.
نعم
Hurry up!
أسرع!
Your Highness.
سموك
Stay calm.
ابق هادئا
I know Princess Hua is very important.
أعلم أن الأميرة هوا مهمة جدا
She represents the attitude of the Hua family,
إنها تمثل الموقف عائلة هوا
the checks and balances in the imperial court
الضوابط والتوازنات في القصة الإمبراطورية
and even the situation on the frontier.
وحتى الوضع على الحدود
However, she's survived
لكن، نجوت
several assassination attempts.
العديد من محاولات الاغتيال
She isn't as feeble as she looks.
ليست ضعيفة كما تبدو
Maybe she has the ability to protect herself.
ربما لديها القدرة لحماية نفسها
Her servant
خادمتها
has even come to seek my help.
حتى جاء لطلب مساعدتي
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
I think we can investigate,
أعتقد أننا نستطيع التحقيق
but we don't have to involve a large number of people.
ولكن ليس علينا إشراك عدد كبير من الناس
Do you remember?
هل تتذكرين؟
Didn't you let her come back
ألم تسمح لها بالعودة
to stir up a storm in the capital
لإثارة العاصفة في العاصمة
to lure the remnants of the evil consort
لإغراء مخلفات القرينة الشريرة
who caused the battle
من تسبب في المعركة
with Jinpo back then?
مع جينبو في ذلك الوقت؟
This
هذا هو أفضل فرصة
is the best chance.
هي أفضل فرصة
Do you really want to give up?
هل تريد حقا أن تستسلم؟
Who...
من
Who can be sure
من يمكنه التأكد من أنها لن تتعرض للخطر هذه المرة
that she won't be in danger this time?
أنها لن تكون في خطر هذه المرة؟
We've used a lot of manpower and resources
لقد استخدمنا الكثير من من القوى البشرية والموارد
to weave this secret net
لغسل هذه الشبكة السرية
covering the whole capital.
تغطي العاصمة بأكملها
If we use it now,
إذا استخدمناه الآن
it might be exposed thoroughly.
قد يكون مكشوفا تماما
Is it worth doing it
هل يستحق القيام بذلك
for Hua Liuli?
من أجل هوا ليولي؟
I doubted the loyalty of the Hua family.
شككت في ولاء عائلة هوا
I tested them
لقد اختبرتهم
over and over again.
مرارا وتكرارا
However,
لكن
I regret it very much now.
يؤسفني ذلك كثيرا الآن
Who are you actually?
في الحقيقة؟
What do you want to do?
ماذا تريدين أن تفعلي؟
Shut up.
اصمت
I'll cut your tongue
سآخذ لسانك
if you talk again.
إذا تحدثت مرة أخرى
(The woman)
"المرأة"
(isn't entirely evil.)
(ليس شريرا تماما)
I'll take you with me later.
سآخذك معي في وقت لاحق
We don't have to bother about you
ليس علينا إزعاجك
after escorting you there.
بعد مرافقتك هناك
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
You won't be harmed for now.
لن تتعرض للأذى في الوقت الحالي
Miss.
الآنسة
Are you always so assertive?
هل أنت صارمة جدًا دائمًا؟
I live a dangerous life.
أنا أعيش حياة خطيرة
I would've died
كنت لأموت
if I acted slowly.
إذا تصرفت ببطء
Are people living a dangerous life
هل يعيش الناس حياة خطيرة
very good at
جيد جدا
assessing the situation?
تقييم الوضع؟
Of course.
بالطبع
Miss.
الآنسة
You're so smart
أنت ذكي جدا
and you can assess the situation.
ويمكنك تقييم الوضع
Why don't you
لماذا لا يمكنك
consider
اعتبار
working with us?
العمل معنا؟
In your dreams.
في أحلامك
Eat.
كلي
Thank you, sister.
شكرًا لك يا أختي
Who is your sister?
من هي أختك؟
Wait.
انتظر
Why is our meal
لماذا وجبتنا
different?
مختلف؟
She looks thinner than you.
تبدو أصغر منك
She should eat more.
يجب أن تأكل أكثر
Thank you, sister.
شكرًا لك يا أختي
I'm warning you.
أنا أحذرك
Don't think of escaping.
لا تفكري في الهروب
You won't get to escape.
لن تهربي
Bootlicker.
بوتليكر
What's the point of
ما الفائدة من
licking her boot?
رهن غطائها؟
talking back to her then?
إذن بالعودة إليها؟
I won't eat.
لن آكل
Why does she bully me
لماذا تتنمر عليّ
after kidnapping you?
بعد أن اختطفتك؟
This is the price you have to pay
هذا هو الثمن الذي عليك دفعه
for helping Crown Prince and Hua Liuli.
لمساعدة ولي عهد وهوا ليولي
(Longjing Street) Master also lets me remind you
(شارع لونغجينغ) المعلم يريد أن يذكرك أيضا
about
عن
your real master.
معلمك الحقيقي
I want to try to trust her.
أريد أن أحاول الوثوق بها
It's just like trusting you.
الأمر مثل الثقة بك
(Blacksmith)
"بلاك سميث"
Dry weather.
الطقس الجاف
Be careful with candles.
انتبه إلى الشموع
Stop crying.
لا تبكي
If you're really scared,
إذا كنت خائفًا حقًا
give me your hand.
أعطني يدك
Who is scared?
من هو خائف؟
I think you're scared instead.
أظن أنك خائف بدلًا من ذلك
How
كيف
would everyone react
رد فعل الجميع
when we're missing?
عندما نكون مفقودين؟
My parents must be very worried.
لا بد أن والديّ قلقين جدًا
Come on, dear.
هيا يا عزيزي
I travelled
سافرت
two streets
شارعان
to buy this.
لشراء هذا
Try it.
جرّبه
You've finally found my favourite food.
لقد وجدت أخيرا الطعام المفضل لي
Master and Madam.
المعلم والسيدة
I've gone to houses where the princess
لقد ذهبت إلى منازل حيث الأميرة
often visits.
كثيرا ما تزور
She isn't there.
إنها ليست هناك
Neither is Hong.
ولا هي هونغ
Go to the music workshop.
اذهبي إلى ورشة الموسيقى
Who would dare to catch
من يجرؤ على الإمساك
someone like Jiamin?
شخص مثل جيامين؟
Come on.
هيا
Try this, too.
جربي هذا أيضًا
This is also delicious.
هذا لذيذ أيضًا
What do you think?
ما رأيك
You have no relative
ليس لديك قريب
in the capital.
في العاصمة
Would no one worry about you?
ألا يقلق أحد بشأنك؟
There may be someone.
قد يكون هناك شخص ما
Who is it?
من هو؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف
Maybe no one
ربما لا أحد
would even care
سوف يهتم حتى
when we're missing
عندما نكون مفقودين
for a night.
ليلة واحدة
Speaking of that,
وبالحدبث عن ذلك
I don't know
لا أعلم
if he'd worry about me.
إذا كان سيقلق عليّ
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
I'll keep you safe.
سأبقيك آمنا
(All assassins sent from Jinpo)
(جميع القاتلين تم إرسالهم من جينبو)
(have been arrested.)
(تم القبض عليهم)
(Almost all moles)
(بل جميع الرخويات)
(lurking beside me)
(دعك بجانبي)
(have been removed.)
(تم إزالتها)
(Still, there's someone)
(ومع ذلك، هناك شخص ما)
(who's targeting Hua Liuli.)
(التي تستهدف هوا ليولي)
(I must have missed something.)
(يجب أن أكون قد اشتقت إلى شيء)
(Who could be)
(من يمكن أن يكون)
(the mastermind?)
(العقل المدبر؟)
Ba.
با
Yes.
نعم
Go to Junior Secretary Pei.
اذهب إلى سكرتير أول بي
Ask him to find a way
اطلب منه إيجاد طريقة
to make A'Wa reveal
لجعل آوا تكشف
whether or not Jinpo
سواء كان جينبو أم لا
still has other people in the capital.
لا يزال لديه أشخاص آخرون في العاصمة
Yes.
نعم
(Liuli.)
"ليولي"
(I'll keep you safe.)
"سأبقيك بأمان"
I've observed in general.
لقد لاحظت بشكل عام
There's no place
لا يوجد مكان
as broken as this in the capital.
مثل هذا في العاصمة
Even the broken temple
حتى المعبد المحطم
near the western suburb
بالقرب من الضاحية الغربية
is way cleaner than this place.
أنظف طريق من هذا المكان
So I think
لذلك أعتقد
this is either
هذه إما
the border suburb of the capital
ضاحية حدود العاصمة
or
أو
out of the capital.
خارج العاصمة
Think of a way to escape
فكر في طريقة للهروب
before leaving the capital.
قبل مغادرة العاصمة
I'll cover you up.
سأغطي عليك
Find someone to save me after that.
اعثر على شخص لإنقاذي بعد ذلك
You?
أنت؟
Can you make it?
هل يمكنك القيام بذلك؟
Why not?
ما السبب؟
I'm not as feeble and useless
أنا لست ضعيفا وعديمة الفائدة
like you.
مثلك
I study military tactics
أدرس التكتيكات العسكرية
and practise martial arts
وممارسة فنون الدفاع عن النفس
from five years old.
من خمس سنوات
I want to save you
أريد أن أنقذك
for General Wei and the few
و القلة
slices of meat just now.
شرائح اللحم للتو
I know.
أعرف
Your whole family
عائلتك بأكملها
has great respect for my mother.
لديها احترام كبير لأمي
Be honest with me.
كن أمينا معي
Are you jealous of me?
هل تشعرين بالغيرة مني؟
I'm not.
لست كذلك
It's useless even if you're jealous of me.
انها عديمة الفائدة حتى لو أنك غيورة مني
My father, mother
أبي وأمي
and brother
وأخوه
pamper me very much.
امزقوني كثيرًا
They always tell me
إنهم يقولون لي دائما
that I am the world's
أنني أفضل ابنة في العالم
best daughter.
أفضل ابنة
I just feel sorry
أنا فقط أشعر بالأسف
for General Wei.
للجنرال يي
She's the best of women.
إنها أفضل النساء
Having a scheming
أن يكون لديك مخطط
and pretentious daughter
و ابنة الطنانة
is the only failure in her life.
هو الفشل الوحيد في حياتها
You know what?
هل تعرف
The more Xi Shi clutched her chest,
كلما ألصقت شي صدرها
the more beautiful she looked.
كلما بدت أكثر جمالا
It talks about
إنها تتحدث عن
people like me.
أشخاص مثلي
Gentle and sickly.
لطيف ومرضي
I'll leave a reputation for ages.
سأترك سمعة للعصور
What a great cause.
يا لها من سبب رائع
Someone is coming.
شخص ما قادم
(Pretentious Hour)
"مهرجان زهور"
What would you like to have
ما الذي تريد الحصول عليه
tonight, Your Highness?
الليلة يا صاحب السمو؟
Biangbiang noodles.
نودلز بيانغبيانغ
I beg your pardon.
أستميحك عذرًا
Why?
لماذا؟
Does my chef not know how to make it?
ألا يعرف الطاهي كيف يصلحه؟
I'll be right back.
حسنا، سأعود
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
Here it is.
ها هو ذا
Your Highness, try it now.
صاحب السمو، جربه الآن
What's this?
ما هذا؟
It's Goodgood noodles.
إنها نودلز جميلة
Two "good".
نودلز جيدة
Isn't it good?
أليس لذيذًا؟
Yes, it is.
أجل، إنه كذلك
(Good good)
(جيد جداً)
♪A new song is played by my fingers♪
♪ أغنية جديدة يعزف بها أصابعي ♪
♪I can't talk or sleep under the moon♪
♪ لا أستطيع التحدث أو النوم تحت القمر ♪
♪I'm missing someone walking around the pavilion♪
♪ أفتقد شخصا ما أتجول حول الجناح ♪
♪I can hardly tell anyone♪
♪ لا أستطيع أن أقول لأي شخص ♪
♪Who will be in this mortal♪
♪ من سيكون في هذه الوفاة ♪
♪Know my heart and how I cry without showing anyone♪
♪ عرفت قلبي وأنت كيف أبكي دون إظهار أي شخص ♪
♪The memory has gone♪
♪ لقد اختفت الذاكرة ♪
♪Whose face is showing in my dream♪
♪ يظهر وجهي في حلمي ♪
♪How many times do I need to go through this♪
♪ كم مرة أحتاج إلى المرور بهذا ♪
♪Crying alone in front of the window♪
♪ الزواج وحده أمام النافذة ♪
♪Hearing the rain last night♪
♪ الاستماع إلى المطر ليلة أمس ♪
♪But my heart will not change♪
♪ لكن قلبي لن يتغير ♪
♪The clouds are being covered by the shadow of the moon♪
♪ الغيوم يتم تغطيتها في ظل القمر ♪
♪Who is rolling up the sleeve with the wind♪
♪ من يدمر النوم بالرياح ♪
♪Not worried about the grudges but for the ones not around♪
♪ لا تقلق بشأن الضغينة ولكن من لا حولها ♪
♪Telling my sorrowfulness in Fengyi Pavilion♪
♪ عزيمة في جناح فنغ يي ♪
♪But it's a shame a few autumns have passed♪
♪ لكنه من المؤسف لقد مرت بعض الأوهام ♪
♪It's hard to balance between the world and the one we love♪
♪ من الصعب التوازن بين العالم بين العالم الذي نحب ♪
♪The clouds are being covered by the shadow of the moon♪
♪ الغيوم يتم تغطيتها في ظل القمر ♪
♪I'm waiting while turning back♪
♪ أنا أنتظر بينما أعود ♪
♪I sighed as the old days are no longer here anymore♪
♪ شاهدت كالأيام الخوالي لم يعد هنا بعد الآن ♪
♪How many worries are there♪
♪ كم عدد الهموم هناك ♪
♪How many of us can grow old together♪
♪ كم الكثير منا يمكن أن يكبر في السن معا ♪
♪I wish you can have the world and the one you love♪
♪ أتمنى أن يكون لديك العالم العالم الذي تحبينه ♪